<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Loknath&#39;s Space</title>
    <link>https://dhar01.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Loknath&#39;s Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 13:22:22 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dhar01.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Resources</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 13:22:22 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/resources/</guid>
      <description>This article contains all the resources I collected over the years and I made for giving back to the community. I hope, visitiors will find this article helpful in their desired areas.
My Resources Notes on Git Find IT jobs in Bangladesh GitHub Collections DevOps Cyber Security </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up SSL for SolrCloud</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/set-up-ssl-for-solrcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/set-up-ssl-for-solrcloud/</guid>
      <description>As I am highly dependent on official documentation, I found that Apache Solr maintain an awesome documentation from which I learned a lot. Setting up SSL can be found here. I am writing this for easier step by step setup.
Happy Searching!
Generate certificate &amp;amp; key From the official documentation, you can generate a self-signed certificate to test your setup. But for the trusted authority, generate a certificate and convert it to .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up SolrCloud for Production</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/set-up-solrcloud-for-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/set-up-solrcloud-for-production/</guid>
      <description>I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with SolrCloud when I started working with this. When I started to learn it and working directly with it - I had done so many mistakes. Even setting up SolrCloud for production was a hassle for me (I&amp;rsquo;m a slow learner). But overtime, I got a hang of it and I think writing an up-to-date guide to set up SolrCloud on production server is a good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Git</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/all_about_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/all_about_git/</guid>
      <description>SCM : Source Control Management.
VCS: Version Control System.
All of the content here is for command line, as I am very comfortable with terminal [and of course Linux].
Basic git syntax: program | action | destination.
For example: git | add | .
Configure git # set your name $ git config user.name &amp;#34;user-name&amp;#34; # set your email $ git config user.email &amp;#34;user-email@example.com&amp;#34; # set global user name $ git config --global user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making custom badges using shields.io</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/custom-badges-github-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/custom-badges-github-profile/</guid>
      <description>When I wanted to customize my GitHub profile, I visited many developers&amp;rsquo; GitHub profiles and used to see some badges which seems cool to me. When I looked at the code behind the profiles, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the slightest idea what was going on. Later, I tried to copy some of the code and paste them into my code, but it couldn&amp;rsquo;t solve the need.
Well, after some reading and searching, I was able to understand how to make them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Dorking (finding information) - OSINT</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/google-fu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/google-fu/</guid>
      <description>Everyone should learn how to search.
(This post contains some google dorking techniques for finding information on the internet. Google is your friend.)
Searching Narrow down search query, use &amp;quot;_something_&amp;quot;.
Ex: &amp;quot;Liverpool&amp;quot;
For exact topic and site:
site: website-name topic-name site: geekforgeeks sql Some terms Term Action filetype: search for a file by its extension cache: view google&amp;rsquo;s cached version of a specified URL intitle: the specified phrase MUST appear in the title of the page allintext: searches specific text contained on any web page allintitle: show pages that contain titles with X characters allinurl: used to fetch results whose URL contains all the specified characters inurl: useful for single keyword, same as allinurl intitle: used to search for various keywords inside the title inanchor: useful when need to search for an exact anchor text used on any links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Overview - 02</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/sql-overview-select/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/sql-overview-select/</guid>
      <description>The SELECT statement is used to query the database and retrieve data that match the criteria.
The SELECT statement has five main clauses to choose from.
Format of the SELECT statement:
SELECT [ALL | DISTINCT] column1[,column2] FROM [table1, table2] [WHERE &amp;#34;conditions&amp;#34;] [GROUP BY &amp;#34;column-list&amp;#34;] [HAVING &amp;#34;conditions] [ORDER BY &amp;#34;column-list&amp;#34; [ASC | DESC] ] Example:
SELECT name, age, salary FROM employee WHERE age &amp;gt; 40; ALL and DISTINCT are keywords used to select either all (default) or the distinct or unique records in query results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Overview - 01</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/sql-overview-basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/sql-overview-basic/</guid>
      <description>This is a note type post for personal reference. I am learning SQL right now and for the learning purpose, I chose two websites:
SQL Course; SQLBolt; For awesome learning experience, my advice is to follow one of them according to your preference. This post is just a summary of those content.
Also, if anyone wants to practice SQL, see Hackerrank&amp;rsquo;s SQL problem-set.
This is still in the early stage. Any suggestions will be appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello There Welcome to my blog!
I am Loknath Dhar, a Linux Enthusiast.
Aspire to become Linux System Administrator and want to find a way into infosec.
This blog is used to share knowledge/ideas of mine.
Music, Movies, Anime, Books, Football &amp;amp; Linux
That&amp;rsquo;s me.
Personal favorite/Things I prefer: (I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this section is right or not but I think it&amp;rsquo;s fun so why not!)
Coding: Python, C++ OS: Pop!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Codeblocks with Freeglut on Linux</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/codeblocks-with-freeglut-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 01:34:53 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/codeblocks-with-freeglut-linux/</guid>
      <description>In my Computer Graphics class, the teacher asked us to setup Codeblocks for the glut. She gave us a tutorial on how to setup Codeblocks on windows but didn&amp;rsquo;t provide any suggestion to set up on Linux. After some searching on google, I was able to setup Codeblocks with Freeglut (which is an alternative to Glut and available on Linux). This is a kind of writeup (or tutorial) on how I was able to setup Codeblocks with Freeglut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Fundamentals walk-through [TryHackMe]</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/web-fundamentals-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 01:34:53 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/web-fundamentals-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>Task 2 A DNS request is made. When browser knows the server&amp;rsquo;s IP address, it ask the server for the web page which is done with a HTTP GET request.
GET is an example of a HTTP verb, which are the different types of request. The server responds to the GET request with the web page content. IF the web page is loading extra resources, like JavaScript, images, or CSS files, those will be retrieved in separate GET requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shodan.io Walk-through [Tryhackme]</title>
      <link>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/shodan-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 01:34:53 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhar01.github.io/posts/shodan-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>Shodan.io is a search engine for the internet of things. There is a room about Shodan in Tryhackme and this walk-through is about that.
Due to the nature of Shodan and its scanning services, the answer is changing all the time. So keep trying.
Task 01 An autonomous system number (ASN) is a global identifier of a range of IP addresses. Basically, large companies like Google, Microsoft have their own ASN for all of the IP addresses they own.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
